# **Ankit Paunikar**

Mobile no: 7715824563 | ankitkpaunikar@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I have over two years of expertise as a software developer, and my job entails gathering and developing requirements from clients for applications I have developed applications using **React.js**, **Next.js**, **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **Node.js** and **Unqork**. Additionally, I have used Jira and Confluence for requirement maintenance.

#### **SKILLS**

- · React.js
- Next.js
- Typescript
- · Microsoft SQL Server
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Figma
- Tableau
- Ungork
- Agile/Scrum Methodology

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineer**

Mumbai, India

Chenoa Information and Software services / Oct 2022 to Current

- Analysing client requirements and coordinating with the team for development timelines and plan testing.
- Working on solutions and coding fixes for requirements using React.js, TypeScript,
   Next.js, JavaScript.
- Working on Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps to manage requirements and timelines.

#### **Associate Software Engineer**

Mumbai, India

Chenoa Information and Software services / Oct 2021 to Oct 2022

- Working with the client on the business workflow and maintaining artifacts and documents for the application
- Working on developing solutions for requirements using **HTML**, **CSS and Unqork**.

- Maintaining **Jira** for the timeline of development and plan testing.
- Preparing and presenting application demos to the client.

# **Professional Projects**

# 1. Portfolio Analysis Application

Project Title : Project Q Client : IQUW

Position : Software Developer
Duration : Oct 2023 to ongoing

# Description

IQUW is a global specialty (re) insurer at Lloyd's (syndicate 1856), underwriting complex risks and developing a new way to combine data, intelligent automation and human expertise to make smart decisions, fast.

# Responsibilities

- Comprehending Figma and designing and developing reuseable UI components.
- The technology stack I utilized in this project includes React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, and Node.js.
- Maintaining documents and code bases for FE, BE, and API specifications using Azure DevOps.

### 2. Wealth Management Application

Project Title : Wealth management

Client : UBS

Position : Software Developer
Duration : Dec 2022 to Aug 2023

#### Description

UBS is a Multinational Investment bank and financial service company, wealth management application will be used by UBS for the wealth management of clients and will streamline and simplify the management of their financial activities through this application.

### Responsibilities

- Designing and developing the UI using Angular, CSS, and Unqork.
- Resolving Bugs and maintaining documents using Jira and Confluence.

#### 3. GIP

Project Title : GIP

Client : Global Infrastructure Partners
Position : Associate Software Engineer

Duration : Jan 2022 to Oct 2022

# Description

Global Infrastructure Partners is a leading global independent infrastructure fund manager. In this, we made multiple applications such as entity management, investment attribute management, new tech onboarding, and user management. We made their process digitally and modified their existing processes.

# Responsibilities

- Communicating with the client and making the business workflow diagrams by using lucidchart.
- Designing using **Figma** and developing the UI using **Html**, **CSS** and **Unqork**.
- Preparing and presenting application demos to the client.
- Maintaining development timelines using Jira.

### **EDUCATION**

Electronics and telecommunication (BE) Ramrao Adik Institution of Technology

Passing year: 2021

Final pointer: 7.01 / 64.54%